J. Peter Lesley Papers 1826-1898 Mss.B.L56
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. General correspondence, 1826-1898 (Box 1)
  - J C W to J. Peter Lesley, 1891 Feb. 25 (Box 26)
  - to "My dear Stevenson", 1891 March 4; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to James Hall, 1891 March 5; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to Ed. O. Ulrich, 1891 March 10; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - The preparation of Greece for the preaching of Paul., 1891 March 14; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to H. S. Tate, 1891 April 18; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to James Hall, 1892 Jan. 27; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to James Hall, 1892 March 24; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to James D. Dana, 1892 May 10; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to Asaph Hall, 1892 May 12; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to "My dear Fulton", 1892 May 13; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to "My dear Powell", 1892 June 6; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to Archibald Blue, 1892 Nov. 3; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - Archibald Geikie to J. P. Lesley, 1892 Dec. 29 (Box 26)
  - to J. C. White, 1893 Jan. 25; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to H. S. Williams, 1893 Jan. 30; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - Plate proofs for the Second Geological Survey of Penna..., 1893 May 6; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, 1893 May 19; Hall, James (Box 26)
  - Archibald Geikie to Mrs. Susan Lesley, 1893 July 13 (Box 26)
  - to E. K. Meyers, 1893 Sept. 26; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - to H. D. Tate, 1893 Dec. 6; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - C. J. Stillé to J. P. Lesley, 1898 March 23 (Box 26)
  - Lesley E. Voorhees to Mr. Ames, 1955 April 12 (Box 26)
  - Charles Lesley Ames to Miss Voorhees., 1955 Sept. 24 (Box 26)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, n.y. Feb. 21; From W. S. Thayer (Box 26)
  - [Operator:] Message for Mr. Leslie [sic]., n.y. May 23 (Box 26)
  - John H to [J. P. Lesley], n.y. May 27 (Box 26)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, n.d.; Irwin, W. H. (Box 26)
  - Scraps, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 26)
  - G. M. Newton to J. P. Lesley. (Box 26)
  - Sarah S. Thayer to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Jan. 17 (Box 26)
  - L. B. Sturgis to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Jan. 28 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Feb. 1 (Box 26)
  - Walt Whitman to J. Peter Lesley, Feb. 26 (Box 26)
  - Annie B. H to Mrs. Susan Lesley, March 3 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Anna Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, March 7 (Box 26)
  - S. Weir Mitchell to J. P. Lesley, March 7 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Anna Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, March 10 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Anna Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, March 10 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Anna Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, March 20 (Box 26)
  - to "Dear Mary", March 24; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - William Channing Gannett to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, April 5 (Box 26)
  - to J. P. Lesley, April 10, 11; Harden, J. W. (Box 26)
  - Abbie B. Greene to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, April 12 (Box 26)
  - G. S. Ellis to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, April 15 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Mary Chew to Miss Hancock, April 23, 26 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Anna Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, April 27 (Box 26)
  - to J. P. Lesley, May 12; Hall, James (Box 26)
  - Henry S. Poole to J. Peter Lesley, May 17 (Box 26)
  - Fidelia Bridges to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, May 19 (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, May 23; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, May 30; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, May 31; Bost, Marie (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, June 1; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - M. E. Howe to Mrs. Susan Lesley, June 7 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, June 8 (Box 26)
  - Joseph Leidy to Mrs. Lesley, June 10 (Box 26)
  - to "Dear Mary", June 13; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, June 20; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - Joseph May to Mrs. Lesley, June 23 (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, June 24; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, July 2; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - Maria R. Towne to Mrs. Lesley, July 6 (Box 26)
  - Louisa Hall to Mrs. Susan P. Lesley, July 8 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, July 8 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson the Mrs. Lesley, July 9 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Anna Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, July 13 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson to Mr. Pearson, July 13 (Box 26)
  - Joseph May to Mrs. Lesley, July 13 (Box 26)
  - Emma Seiler to Mrs. Susan Lesley, July 13 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, July 14 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, July 16 (Box 26)
  - Maria R. Towne to Mrs. Lesley, July 20 (Box 26)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, July 23; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - Nathan Hale to Susie I. Lesley, July 23 (Box 26)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, July 26 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Laura Guinotte to Miss Lesley, July 27 (Box 26)
  - to "Dear Mary", July 30; Swan, Martha L. (Box 26)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Aug. 6; Swan, Martha L. (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Aug. 7 (Box 27)
  - to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Aug. 8; Furness, William Henry (Box 27)
  - Mrs. Gertrude G. Biddle to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Aug. 10 (Box 27)
  - Rebe to "My Dear Mary", Aug. 10 (Box 27)
  - Margie Eurness? to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Aug. 11 (Box 27)
  - Maria R. Towne to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Aug. 12 (Box 27)
  - Margie Furness to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Aug. 15 (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Aug. 19 (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Aug. 22 (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Aug. 22 (Box 27)
  - to "Dear Mary", Aug. 26; Swan, Martha L. (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Aug. 29 (Box 27)
  - to "Dear Mary", Sept. 2; Swan, Martha L. (Box 27)
  - Cornelia Loring to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Sept. 8 (Box 27)
  - R E To Hannah, Sept. 15 (Box 27)
  - Julia Morton to Mrs. Lesley, Sept. 15 (Box 27)
  - S. M. Hall to J. Peter Lesley, Sept. 18 (Box 27)
  - D. Honeyman to J. Peter Lesley, Sept. 20 (Box 27)
  - to J. P. Lesley, Sept. 24; Hall, James (Box 27)
  - Mrs. Maria weston Chapman to Mr. Peter Lesley, Sept. 26 (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Oct. 10 (Box 27)
  - Sarah Moore Grimké to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Oct. 15 (Box 27)
  - E. F. Knowlton to Mrs. Lesley, Oct. 24 (Box 27)
  - Maria R. Towne to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Oct. 24 (Box 27)
  - Elizabeth L. Smith to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Oct. 25 (Box 27)
  - J. Lesley to Edouard Desor, Nov. 3 (Box 27)
  - Annie W. Davis to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Nov. 5 (Box 27)
  - William Channing Gannett to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Nov. 9 (Box 27)
  - Fanny T. Morland to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Nov. 11 (Box 27)
  - to "Dear Mary", Nov. 11; Swan, Martha L. (Box 27)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Nov. 14; Swan, Martha L. (Box 27)
  - C. T. Leonard to Mrs. Lesley, Nov. 19 (Box 27)
  - Mrs. Ann Gilchrist to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Nov. 21 (Box 27)
  - Hale to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Nov. 23 (Box 27)
  - S. S. Thayer to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Dec. 5 (Box 27)
  - Georgina Lowell Putnam to Mrs. Lesley, Dec. 17 (Box 27)
  - Sarah Moore Grimké to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Dec. 20 (Box 27)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, Dec. 23; Bost, Sophie (Box 27)
  - Catharine Cummings to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Dec. 29 (Box 27)
  - to "Dear Mary", Dec. 30; Swan, Martha L. (Box 27)
  - to Peter Lesley, Sr., Sunday morning; Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 27)
  - Helen C. Jenks to Mrs. Lesley, Sunday evening (Box 27)
  - Elizabeth Gay to Mrs. Susie I. Lesley, Sunday (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Sunday (Box 27)
  - Horace Howard Furness to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Monday evening (Box 27)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, Monday evening; Hall, James (Box 27)
  - Mrs. Anna Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Monday evenong (Box 27)
  - John Strykes to J. Peter Lesley, Monday evening (Box 27)
  - to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Monday; Thompson, R. E. (Box 27)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, Tuesday morning; Hall, James (Box 27)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, Tuesday evening; Hall, James (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley, Tuesday evening (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Tuesday evening (Box 27)
  - Ann Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Tuesday evening (Box 27)
  - E. L. Head? to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Tuesday (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Tuesday (Box 27)
  - Letter to Mrs. Lesley, Tuesday (Box 27)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, Wednesday; Hall, James (Box 27)
  - Ellen McMurtrie to Mrs. Lesley, Wednesday (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Thursday (Box 27)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley, Thursday (Box 27)
  - E. L. Kendall to Mrs. Lesley, Thursday (Box 27)
  - Mary H. Loines to Mrs. Lesley, Thursday (Box 27)
  - L. C. Towne to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Thursday (Box 27)
  - Samuel Longfellow to Mrs. Lesley, Friday (Box 27)
  - Biographical sketch of R. M. S. Jackson (Box 28)
  - Mrs. Lucretia Longshore Blankenburg to----- (Box 28)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, Bost, Sophie (Box 28)
  - M. J. Burleigh to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Concernign John H. Harden (Box 28)
  - Adolphe Favre to J. Peter Lesley, Secretaire de la Société philosophique de Philadelphie (Box 28)
  - Mrs. Annie Adams Fields to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley (Box 28)
  - to J. P. Lesley, Frazer, John Fries, 1812-1872 (Box 28)
  - to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Furness, William Henry (Box 28)
  - to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Furness, William Henry (Box 28)
  - to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley, Furness, William Henry (Box 28)
  - to Peter Lesley, Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909 (Box 28)
  - to Mrs. Lesley, Hale, Susan (Box 28)
  - to J. P. Lesley, Hall, James (Box 28)
  - to J. Peter Lesley, Hall, James (Box 28)
  - Sarah E. Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Mrs. Ann Coffin Davis Hallowell to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Memorandum to J. Peter Lesley, Harden, J. W. (Box 28)
  - E. L. Head to Mrs. Susan I. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Isac S. Holbrook to J. Peter Lesley (Box 28)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. J. P. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. J.P. Lesley (Box 28)
  - Anna Jackson to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 28)
  - Auguste Langel to J. Peter Lesley (Box 28)
  - Analysis of Baer's lands, Somerset County Penna., for Persifor Frazer, Jr., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - The Arkism fo Rivers, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Chapter on the Devil, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Chicques Rock, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Comments on: The Ancient World by D. T. Ansted, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning architecture; the arch and Gothic architecture, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning C. O. Müller's Doric Race, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning caves, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning divorce, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning his edition of the travels of Johann Bernouilli, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning immortality, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning language, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning mountains, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning music, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning numbers, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning the Gabali, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning the human foot, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning the legend of Samson, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning the schools fo painting..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning the true portait of Christ..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning vases..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning water..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning the word "Dilemma", Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning words, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Concerning the words: tote, carry, bear, etc., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Dr. Milligen's book: Mind and Matter, extracts and observations, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - "Elementa Rossica", Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Essay On the plebeian classes, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Examination of the New Testament for non-scholastic Truth, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Fire and Water; the Begining and the End of All Things, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Genealogy from Adam to the present..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Geological reports..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Is slavery Sin?, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Jewish scriptures, the bane of Christendom, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Lecture on entomology, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Lecture on Stonehenge, England, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Letters to myself..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Lists of persons to whom was sent the pamphlet on California mosses..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous notes concerning polar exploration, geological publications, etc., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous writings..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Notes on a possible Adite element in Egypt Read before the APS Oct. 21, 1881, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Notes on the deities of the Rig Veda, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Note on the Enead Aphrodite, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Notes on "Grotes Greece", Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Note on the origin of the name Israel, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - On popular stuperstitions, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - On religion and Parker's ide's on religion, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - On the value of a general education, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Plain reason why I am not a Calvinist, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Pythagorus and Christ, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Scheme for lecturing on geology, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Short stories, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Short writings, poems, maps, geological notes, etc..., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Astory, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Theology as a science, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - The Furnace, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - The Triangle, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - to James Lesley, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - to Simon Stevens, reporting on the Pond Bank resources Penna., Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - View of the progress of political economy in Europe since the 16th Century, from lectures by Travers Twiss, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - What is the object of Christianity?, Lesley, J. P., (J. Peter), 1819-1903 (Box 28)
  - Marriage form... copied by J. P. Lesley (Box 29)
  - Letter to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - Joseph May to Mrs. Lesley (Box 29)
  - Joseph May to Mrs. Lesley (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous notes fo J. Peter Lesley pertaining to the Geological Survey of Pennsylvania (Box 29)
  - Julia Norton to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - Anna D. Scott to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - Anna D. Scott to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - Emma L. Seidensticker to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - E. S. Turner to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - Mrs. Margie Turner to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - to Mrs.Susan Lesley, Towne, Alice N. (Box 29)
  - M. R. Towne to Mrs.Susan Lesley (Box 29)
  - Mary. E. Walker to Mrs. Susan Lesley (Box 29)
    Identified by Sydney Nathans, Duke Univeristy, as dating from Jan. 5 and 6, 1853.
- Series II. Correspondence with Joseph Lesley, 1834-1887; Mss. B L56.2; 0.5 Linear feet ca. 300 items (Box 1)
  Correspondence in both directions between J. Peter Lesley and his brother Joseph, arranged chronologically. Then correspondence includes several elegant and lengthy letters written by Joseph Lesley during his travels in Europe, 1855-1857, many of which are illustrated with sketches, and some important letters written while surveying in the coal fields of Kentucky and Arkansas.
  Peter Lesley's letters not surprisingly also include important discussion of his work with the Pennsylvania Geological Survey, with detailed descriptions of the coal and iron fields, again illustrated with sketches.
  Finally, the series includes a biographical sketch (9 pp.) of Joseph Lesley written by his grandson Allen.
- Series III. Notebooks, 1839-1896; Mss. B L56.1; 24.0 Volume(s) (Volume 1-24)
  Notebooks of Egyptology, geology, philology; diaries.
  Also available as History of Science Film 12.
  - (Transferred) Notes Geological Survey Fall of 1851. 1- Pottsville district. Also, levels of survey near Llewelly, for Cresson, by B. S. Lymann, Nov. 1862.; 1; ca 100 p. (Othertype Reel 8)
  - Egyptian Hieroglyphs..., 1867-1868; 2; ca 75 p. (Othertype Reel 8)
  - Geology Survey... Cape Breton by B. S. Lyman, 1863; 3; ca 50 p. (Othertype Reel 8)
  - Geology Survey... Emigh's Cape, 4; ca 75 p. (Othertype Reel 8)
  - A. McKinley 7 Mountains, Warrior Ridge. Contains a copy of my finished report of the year 1839-1840, 5; ca 150 p. (Othertype Reel 8)
  - Egyptian Hieroglyphs. Notebook - Egyptology, Zend Avesta, etc., 6; ca 129 p. (Othertype Reel 8, 9)
  - Etymology and Geographical Names Biblical Texts, 7; ca 175 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Egyptian Hieroglyphs Egyptian etymology or arkism, 8; ca 40 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Egyptian Hieroglyphs Egyptian etymology or arkism, 9; ca 25 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Egyptian etymology or arkism, 10; ca 45 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Egyptian Hieroglyphs Egyptian etymology or arkism, 11; ca 75 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Geological Accounts volume 1, 1874-1878; 12; ca 175 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Geological Accounts volume 2, 1878-1881; 13; ca 190 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Geological Accounts volume 3, 1882-1888; 14; ca 190 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Geological Accounts volume 4, 1888-1896; 15; ca 190 p (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Diary volume 1, 1874; 16; ca 190 p. (Othertype Reel 9)
  - Diary volume 2, 1874-1875; 17; ca 190 p. (Othertype Reel 9,10)
  - Diary volume 3, 1875-1876; 18; ca 190 p. (Othertype Reel 10)
  - Diary volume 4, 1877-1881; 19; ca 190 p. (Othertype Reel 10)
  - Dictionary of fossils found in Penns and else where ca 300 p. (auto 1), 20 (Othertype Reel 10,11)
  - Poetic Writings by J. P. Lesley, 21; ca 200 p. (Othertype Reel 11)
  - Miscellany pertaining to: Antiguities, the Deluge, entomology, geology, ancient man, etc., 22; ca 300 p. (Othertype Reel 11)
  - Philology, 23; ca 400 p. (Othertype Reel 11,12)
  - Journals, 1844-1845; 24; ca 400 p. 4 Volumes (Othertype Reel 13)
- Graphics., A sample of the graphics available from the J. P. Lesley Papers.
  - Bust of J. Peter Lesley., ca. 1853; 1.0 Item(s); Frontal portrait of Lesley.
  - Profile of J. Peter Lesley., ca. 1850; 1.0 Item(s); Profile of Lesley with glasses.
  - Portrait of J. Peter Lesley and young son., ca. 1845; 1.0 Item(s); Group portrait of Lesley and son.
  - Bust of Susan Lesley, 3/4 profile., ca. 1850; 1.0 Photograph(s); Portrait of Susan Lesley.
  - Half length portrait of somber Susan Lesley in profile., ca. 1850; 1.0 Item(s); Portrait of Susan Lesley with hands on lap.
  - Painted miniature portrait of Susan Lesley., ca. 1848; 1.0 Item(s); Bust length portrait of Susan Lesley.